Jazmin Logrono

New York City (315)744-8902 <u>jmlogron@syr.edu</u> <u>GitHub</u>

Data Scientist Graduate with data collection, data analysis, and reporting experience to answer key stakeholder questions. Goal-oriented, curious, creative, and problem-solving mentality capable of executing research projects promptly, maintaining relationships with interested parties, and providing them with reliable business solutions for data-driven decision-making.

Experience

JAN 2022 – AUG 2022

Analyst | Judicial Council of California | San Francisco, CA

Met with team members to discuss projects and business rules. Performed data collection and data quality analysis to identify anomalies. Prepared reports explaining results to stakeholders. Improved processes by creating scripts in R programming language to automate processes involving data extraction from the Data Warehouse, data cleansing and data transforming for reports. Updated dashboards in Tableau, restored processes written in STATA and responded to ad-hoc requests involving analysis, reporting or data management.

JUL 2019 – JUN 2021

Programmer/Designer | SoundVision | Novato, CA

Prepared proposals, budgets and designs for residential lighting and control systems. Met with Clients and Architects to discuss designs, changes, and options. Successfully programmed and repaired lighting control systems to meet Client standards.

JAN 2018 - JUL 2019

Project Engineer | kW Engineering | Oakland, CA

Performed data collection and data analysis to answer essential research questions regarding building operation and efficiency. Collaborated with stakeholders to initiate repairs and recommended

programming changes based on data-driven insights. Presented results to building engineers and other interested parties.

FEB 2015 – JAN 2018

Field Service Engineer | ProAutomated | San Francisco Bay Area, CA

Programmed and repaired lighting control systems per user requirements and State code.

Communicated with interested parties through phone calls, meetings, and status updates written via email or on Salesforce. Trained technical and non-technical users on utilizing systems and making programming changes. Team leader for six Field Service Engineers.

JUL 2013 – JAN 2015

Laboratory Technician | Porous Materials Incorporated | Ithaca, NY

Successfully executed laboratory analysis on Client samples and communicated with Clients to explain results. Calibrated, maintained laboratory equipment, and traveled to calibrate and repair Client machines. Trained Clients on effective ways to test their samples.

Education

DEC 2022

Master of Science Applied Data Science | Syracuse University | Syracuse, NY

Relevant Coursework: Big Data Analytics, Business Analytics, Applied Machine Learning, Statistics, Text Mining, Natural Language Processing, Data Warehouse, Data Visualization, Data Concepts & Database Administration, and Cloud Management.

MAY 2013

Bachelor of Science Physics | Le Moyne College | Syracuse, NY

Relevant Coursework: Probability Theory, Calculus I, II, III, Differential Equations, and Linear Algebra. Minored in Philosophy.

Certifications

SEP 2021

Tableau 2022 A-Z: Hands-On Tableau Training for Data Science | Udemy

AUG 2021

SQL – MySQL for Data Analytics and Business Intelligence | Udemy

JUL 2021

Machine Learning | Cornell University

MAR 2021

Python Programming | Cornell University

Projects

Opioid Epidemic Analysis - Project Link

Project Summary: The United States is currently struggling with an Opioid Epidemic crisis, and, unfortunately, the problem stems from doctors overprescribing Opioid Medications. As a research project, my team analyzed the Medicare Part D Prescribers by Provider and Drug dataset hosted by the Centers for Medicare & Medicaid Services to identify key factors of the Opioid Epidemic.

Analysis: The analysis was successfully implemented in R-programming language to create Data Visualizations, run Statistical Analysis, and Data Mining techniques, like Decision Trees, Naïve Bayes, Association Rules Mining, and Clustering.

Results: States with excessive use of Opioids due to Prescriptions include Illinois, Georgia, Colorado, and Alabama. Additionally, Family Practices, Emergency Medicine, General Surgery, and General Practices are among the Prescribers that excessively prescribe Opioids, which is alarming since most of us visit Family Practices and General Practices for care. Raising awareness of the dangers of Opioid Addiction and Overdose at Practices and implementing early intervention programs in high-risk States can help mitigate the Opioid Epidemic crisis. Finally, Fentanyl, Hydrocodone-Acetaminophen, Hydromorphone HCL, Methadone HCL, and Oxycodone are among the high-risk Prescriptions driving the Opioid Epidemic.

Wikipedia Toxic Comments - Project Link

Project Summary: The internet has introduced new ways for people to express themselves, but also new ways to insult others. Toxic expressions have a negative impact on internet users. Identifying harmful expressions can help mediate the exposure to toxic comments and the impacts on internet users and their mental health. As a research project, my team analyzed Wikipedia Comments to detect unhealthy online behavior.

Analysis: The analysis was successfully implemented in Python programming to Tokenize and Vectorize the Wikipedia Comments corpus and execute Text Mining techniques like Naïve Bayes, Latent Dirichlet Allocation, Clustering, and Support Vector Machines models.

Results: Toxic comments typically fall into two categories, hate speech and online harassment. Social media has vastly changed how people communicate; children and teenagers are using the internet now more than ever, resulting in exposure to harassment at earlier ages. Although drastic, some censorship on Wikipedia might result in better online communities and, therefore, less online harassment.

Avocado Analysis - Project Link

Project Summary: People are becoming more aware of the health impacts caused by poor eating habits. As awareness increases, people seek out healthier foods. Avocados are beneficial for the heart and eyes. They help in growth and development, help lower blood pressure, and can help consumers lose weight. The health benefits offered by Avocados have made them a popular commodity in the United States. California is the leading Avocado producing State in America. As a research project, my team analyzed Avocado production and prices, and how precipitation levels in different California Counties affect production and prices throughout the United States.

Analysis: The analysis was successfully implemented in Python programming. Data Visualizations, Statistics, and Forecasting techniques like ARIMA and Prophet provided insights into Avocado production in California Counties and prices throughout the United States.

Results: Overall, California expects to increase its Avocado production to meet consumption demands. Fluctuating precipitation levels will continue to affect production and prices. Currently, most Avocados get imported from Mexico, which also affects pricing. States closer to the Mexican border, like Texas, can expect relatively low Avocado prices compared to States like Idaho and Connecticut, where prices are comparatively higher.

Skills

Python • R • SQL • Tableau • PowerBI • AWS • Azure • Algorithms

Microsoft Office • Visual Studio • Jupyter Notebooks • Data Management

Communication • Presentation • Time Management • Problem Solver

Activities

Yoga • Golf • Photography • Hiking • Philosophizing • Learning • Volunteer